u2 =[
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "апельсин",
    "Back": "orange"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "банан",
    "Back": "banana"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "бифштекс",
    "Back": "steak"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "борщ",
    "Back": "borsch"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "бублик",
    "Back": "bagel"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "булка",
    "Back": "white bread"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "булочка",
    "Back": "small roll"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "бульон",
    "Back": "buillon"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "бутерброд",
    "Back": "open-faced sandwich"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "вино",
    "Back": "wine"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "виноград",
    "Back": "grapes"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "вода",
    "Back": "water"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "гамбургер",
    "Back": "hamburger"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "горчица	",
    "Back": "mustard"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "гриб",
    "Back": "mushroom"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "закуски",
    "Back": "appetizers"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "икра",
    "Back": "caviar"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "капуста",
    "Back": "cabbage"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "картофель",
    "Back": "potato/potatoes"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "каша",
    "Back": "hot cereal"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "кефир",
    "Back": "kefir"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "колбаса",
    "Back": "sausage"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "конфеты",
    "Back": "candy"
  },
  {
    "Front": "котлета",
    "Back": "cutlet"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "котлеты по-киевски",
    "Back": "chicken Kiev"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "кофе",
    "Back": "coffee"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "курица",
    "Back": "chicken"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "лимон",
    "Back": "lemon"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "лук",
    "Back": "onion(s)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "макароны",
    "Back": "macaroni"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "масло",
    "Back": "butter"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "минеральная вода",
    "Back": "mineral water"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "молоко",
    "Back": "milk"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "морковь",
    "Back": "carrot(s)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "мороженое",
    "Back": "ice cream"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "мясо",
    "Back": "meat"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "мясное ассорти",
    "Back": "cold cuts assortment"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "напиток",
    "Back": "drink"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "овощи",
    "Back": "vegetables"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "огурец",
    "Back": "cucumber"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "оливье",
    "Back": "potato salad with chicken"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "пельмени",
    "Back": "pelmeni"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "перец",
    "Back": "pepper"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "печенье",
    "Back": "cookie"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "пиво",
    "Back": "beer"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "пирожки",
    "Back": "baked or fried dumplings"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "пицца",
    "Back": "pizza"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "помидор",
    "Back": "tomato"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "пюре",
    "Back": "creamy mashed potatoes"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "рис",
    "Back": "rice"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "рыба",
    "Back": "fish"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "салат",
    "Back": "salad"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "сахар",
    "Back": "sugar"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "сладкое",
    "Back": "dessert"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "сметана",
    "Back": "sour cream"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "сок",
    "Back": "juice"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "соль",
    "Back": "salt"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "соус",
    "Back": "sauce"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "суп",
    "Back": "soup"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "сыр",
    "Back": "cheese"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "тесто",
    "Back": "dough"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "торт",
    "Back": "cake"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "фарш",
    "Back": "ground meat"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "фрукты",
    "Back": "fruit"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "хлеб",
    "Back": "bread"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "чай",
    "Back": "tea"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "чеснок",
    "Back": "garlic"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "шашлык",
    "Back": "shish kabob"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "щи",
    "Back": "cabbage soup"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "яблоко",
    "Back": "apple"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "яичница",
    "Back": "cooked (not boiled) eggs"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "яйцо",
    "Back": "egg"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "буфет",
    "Back": "snack bar"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "булочная",
    "Back": "bakery"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "гастроном",
    "Back": "grocery store"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "кафе",
    "Back": "cafe"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "кафетерий",
    "Back": "snack bar"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "продовольственный магазин",
    "Back": "grocery store"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "универсам",
    "Back": "self-service grocery store"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "аллергия",
    "Back": "allergy"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "вегетарианец/вегетерианка",
    "Back": "vegetarian"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "блюдо",
    "Back": "dish"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "бутылка",
    "Back": "bottle"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "второе",
    "Back": "main course"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "копейка",
    "Back": "kopeck"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "кухня",
    "Back": "cuisine, style of cooking"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "меню",
    "Back": "menu"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "официант/официанка",
    "Back": "waiter/waitress"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "первое",
    "Back": "first course (always soup)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "порция",
    "Back": "portion"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "продукты",
    "Back": "groceries"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "счёт",
    "Back": "bill, check"
  },
  {
    "Type": "noun",
    "Front": "чаевые",
    "Back": "tip"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "вкусный",
    "Back": "tasty, good"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "минеральный",
    "Back": "mineral"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "молочный",
    "Back": "milk, dairy"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "мясной",
    "Back": "meat"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "никакой",
    "Back": "none"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "свежий",
    "Back": "fresh"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adj",
    "Front": "томатный",
    "Back": "tomato"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "быть",
    "Back": "to be"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "брать/взять",
    "Back": "to take"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "готовить/приготовить",
    "Back": "to cook, prepare"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "делать/сделать",
    "Back": "to do, make"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "думать/подумать",
    "Back": "to think"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "есть/съесть",
    "Back": "to eat"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "заказывать",
    "Back": "to order"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "идти/пойти",
    "Back": "to go (on foot or within a city)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "найти",
    "Back": "to find"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "обедать/пообедать",
    "Back": "to have lunch"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "писать/написать",
    "Back": "to write"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "пить/выпить",
    "Back": "to drink"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "показывать/показать",
    "Back": "to show"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "покупать/купить",
    "Back": "to buy"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "попасть",
    "Back": "to manage to get in"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "рассказывать/рассказать",
    "Back": "to narrate, tell (a story)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "решать/решить",
    "Back": "to decide"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "слышать/слушать",
    "Back": "to hear"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "смотреть/посмотреть",
    "Back": "to watch"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "советовать/посоветовать",
    "Back": "to advise"
  },
  {
    "Type": "verb",
    "Front": "ужинать/поунжинать",
    "Back": "to have supper"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adv",
    "Front": "пока",
    "Back": "meanwhile"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adv",
    "Front": "просто",
    "Back": "simply, just"
  },
  {
    "Type": "adv",
    "Front": "страшно",
    "Back": "terribly"
  },
  {
    "Type": "prep",
    "Front": "без",
    "Back": "without"
  },
  {
    "Type": "prep",
    "Front": "с",
    "Back": "with"
  },
  {
    "Type": "subjectless",
    "Front": "нельзя",
    "Back": "it is not permitted"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Во-первых..., Во-вторых...",
    "Back": "In the first place..., in the second place..."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Дайте, пожалуйста, счёт!",
    "Back": "Check, please!"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Если говорить о себе, то...",
    "Back": "If I use myself as an example, then..."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Минуточку!",
    "Back": "Just a minute!"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Мы точно попадём.",
    "Back": "We'll get in for sure."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Получите!",
    "Back": "Take it! (said when paying)"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Пошли!",
    "Back": "Let's go!"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Принесите, пожалуйста, меню!.",
    "Back": "Please bring a menu."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Смотря...",
    "Back": "It depends..."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "С одной стороны..., с другой стороны...",
    "Back": "On the one hand..., on the other hand..."
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Что вы (нам, мне) посоветуете взять?",
    "Back": "What do you advise (us, me) to order?"
  },
  {
    "Type": "phrase",
    "Front": "Что ещё нужно?",
    "Back": "What else is needed?"
  }
]